(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T05:53:47.992346",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
悲しみに濡れた月が静かに
The moon is soaked in sadness,
大地を赤く赤く染めて消える
quietly painting the land red and fading away.
僕の声が聞こえますか
Can you hear my voice?
殺伐としたこの時代で
In this bloodthirsty era,
僕は僕でいられますか
can I stay true to myself?
ココロ溢れ出す涙は
The tears overflowing from my heart
きっと未来を求めてる証なのだ
are surely proof of seeking a future.
今の無力をお嘆かないで
Don't lament your powerlessness now;
前を見つめて
gaze straight ahead.
You can get it over over the clouds
季節を移ろう風のざわめき
The rustling wind shifts the seasons,
終わりの見えない戦いへの序曲
a prelude to an endless battle.
人は何故に忘れていくの
Why do people forget
ありふれたこの日常に
that in this ordinary, everyday life,
かけがえのないものがあると
there is something irreplaceable?
ボロボロになった羽根でも
Even with tattered wings,
誰かを想うその気持ちがあるなら
if you have the feeling of thinking of someone,
どんな苦しみに向かっても
no matter what pain you face,
飛んでいけるさ
you can fly away.
You can get it over over the clouds
悲しみに濡れた月が静かに
A moon wet with sorrow, oh so quietly
大地を赤く赤く染めて消える
tints the earth red, so red, and disappears.
僕の声が聞こえますか
Do you hear my voice?
殺伐としたこの時代で
In these brutal times we live in,
僕は僕でいられますか
can I remain myself?
ココロ溢れ出す涙は
Tears pouring from my heart
きっと未来を求めてる証なの
are surely proof that I seek the future.
今の無力を嘆かないで前を見つめて
Don't lament your powerlessness now, look ahead.
You can get it over
over the clouds
季節を移ろう風のざわめき
The wind stirs as it changes the season,
終わりの見えない戦いへの序曲
a prelude for a battle with no end in sight.
人はなぜに忘れてくの
Why do people forget
ありふれたこの日常に
that in this ordinary, everyday life
かけがえのないものがあると
there are things that are irreplaceable?
ボロボロになった羽根でも
Though your wings may be frayed and tattered,
誰かを想うその気持ちがあるなら
if you have feelings of thinking of someone,
どんな苦しみに向かっていても飛んで行けるさ
you can fly toward whatever suffering awaits.
You can get it over
over the clouds
僕の声が聞こえますか
Do you hear my voice?
殺伐としたこの時代で
In these brutal times we live in,
僕は僕でいられますか
can I remain myself?
ココロ溢れ出す涙は
Tears pouring from my heart
きっと未来を求めてる証なの
are surely proof that I seek the future.
ボロボロになった羽根でも
Though your wings may be frayed and tattered,
誰かを想うその気持ちがあるなら
if you have feelings of thinking of someone,
どんな苦しみに向かっていても飛んで行けるさ
you can fly toward whatever suffering awaits.
You can get it over
over the clouds
ということで皆さん、ただいま！ホロライブ2期生の獅白ぼたん です！
So everyone, welcome back! I'm Hololive 2nd Gen's Shishiro Botan!
今日はですね、2期生が2周年…2…2…2周年ということで盛り上がってます！
Today, well, 2nd Gen's 2nd anniversary... 2... 2... 2nd anniversary, so we're super hyped!
えー、ありがとうございます！まだまだホロライブに入ってペーペーの私たちですがね、見守っていただければ嬉しいです。
Thank you so much! We're still newbies who just joined Hololive, but we'd be happy if you keep watching over us.
ということで今日は2周年ライブにさせていただきました。ちょっとステージね、見てほしい。
So today we got to hold this 2nd anniversary live. I want you guys to check out the stage, look!
ロゴ！ちゃんと言って作ってもらって、後ろにね、SSRBの、こっちもいこうか。こっちほら見て！
The logo! They made it properly for us, and right behind us, SSRB's... let's go over here. Look at this!
ネオンがすごい光ってるよ。これね、ちょっとね、歌ってる時とかね、結構ビカビカ光ってね、一緒に演出してくれるようになってるんで。
The neon is glowing so brightly. You know, while singing and stuff, it flashes brilliantly to coordinate with the performance.
ま、今日はこういうね、SSRBも一緒にお祝いに駆けつけてくれましたということで、あの、見ていただければ嬉しいなと思ってます。
Well, today SSRB rushed over to celebrate with us too, so I'd be super happy if you all check it out.
おお、すごい！わーい、広ーい！すごいね。
Oh, wow! Yay, it's so big! That's amazing.
いや、去年、えーとね、私、まあ前からちょっと言ってたんですけど、あんまりやっぱりその入った当初歌がうまくなく、へにゃへにゃ歌だったんですけど、
Man, last year, as I've been saying for a while, when I first joined my singing wasn't very good, it was wobbly and weak,
まあ、2年も経てばね、多少はちょっとは歌えるようになったのかな？まあ、色々練習したりとかみんなと一緒に歌わせてもらったりとかして、まあ多少1/3ぐらい腹から声が出るようになったので、
but after 2 years, I guess I've gotten a bit better at singing? Practicing various things and singing together with everyone, now I can project from my gut about a third of the way,
今日は その成果を見せられたらいいかな と思っております。じゃあこの後もね、たくさんゲストの方もね、ありがたいことに駆けつけてくれましたので、楽しんでいただけると嬉しいなと思っておりますんで。
so I hope I can show off the results of that today. After this, thankfully a lot of guests rushed over too, so I hope you'll enjoy that!
はい。最後までよかったら見ていってください！ありがとね！じゃあ次の曲いってみましょうか！じゃあ次はなんだろうな？気になる？じゃあちょっと次の曲いってみましょう！
Yeah. Please keep watching till the end! Thanks! Shall we go to the next song? Wonder what it is? Curious? Let's check out the next song!
そんな優しくしないで
Don’t be so kind to me
どんな顔すればいいの？
I don't know how to react
積み重ねた言葉で見えないよ 君の横顔
With all those words piling up, I can't see your profile.
どこだっけ？失くした鍵は見つからないままで
Where is it? I can’t find the key I lost
ため息…すれ違いに意地張って疲れてしまう
Sigh... when we disagree, my stubbornness tires you out.
ほんの少し遠く
You are a little too far
手は届かない
out of my reach,
ちゃんと掴みたいのかな 君のその影
but maybe I should catch your shadow.
そんな優しくしないで
Don’t be so kind to me
ほら また傷つけ合って
Look, we’re hurting each other again.
積み重ねたウソでもう動けなくなってる
I can't move with all the lies piling up.
そんな目でみつめないで
Don't look at me like that,
どんな顔すればいいの？
I don't know how to react.
迷ってばっかり
I'm utterly lost.
そんな優しくしないで
Don't be so kind to me
どんな顔すればいいの？
What kind of face should I make?
幾千の日々を
Through countless days
君と過ごしてきたんだろう
I've spent with you, haven't I?
それでも交わした言葉は少なすぎるね
Even so, the words we exchanged are far too few
ほんの少し近く
Just a little closer,
君との距離がうまく掴めないんだ
I can't quite grasp the distance between us
あとちょっとなのに！
Even though we're so close!
そんな優しくしないで
Don't be so kind to me,
ほらまた傷つけあって
Look, we're hurting each other again
積み重ねたウソじゃもう動けなくなってる
I can't move anymore with all the lies piling up
君の言葉 本当の声を
Your words, hiding your true voice
隠して 口ずさむこのメロディ
Humming this melody to myself
ゆっくりと変わってく
Entrusting myself to a heart
心に身を任せて
That is slowly changing
自分自身のこともわからないし
I don't even understand myself,
君のこと知りたい気もするけど
And yet I want to know you too
ぶつかる気持ちを少し抑えて
Holding back my conflicting feelings slightly,
見えない壁 壁伝いに探すよ
I search along the invisible walls
そんな優しくしないで
Don't be so kind to me,
ほらまた傷つけあって
Look, we're hurting each other again
積み重ねたウソはもう辛いだけだからね？
Because the lies piling up are already too painful, right?
すぐに会いに行きたいけど言葉は見つからないし
I want to go see you right away, but I can't find the words
最後の1ページくらい君には笑顔見せたい！
On the final page, at least, I want to show you my smile!
いえーい！
Yay!
ぼたん先輩、2周年おめでとうございます！
Botan-senpai, happy 2nd anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日ね、我々ね、はい。水着。
Today, you know, we're wearing... swimsuits.
かわいい！
So cute!
なんか違う、なんか違う！
Something's different, something's wrong!
思ってたのと違う！
It's different from what I expected!
思ってたのと違うわ、なんか
It's different from what I expected, somehow.
え、水着でしょ？え、じゃあ私、水着でしょ？
Huh, swimsuits right? Huh, well me, swimsuits right?
せっかくなのでね、夏っぽいポーズをちょっとみんなでスクショ撮れたらいいかなって
Since we have the chance, maybe we can all take a summer-like screenshot together!
夏っぽいポーズ？夏っぽいポーズなんかある？
A summer-like pose? Is there any summer-like pose?
いや、ここ今2人で完結して
Wait, the two of us just wrapped this up—
水しぶきだ！水しぶきどんなの？
Water splashes! What kind of water splashes?
きゅ、きゅ、なんか違うな！やめて！
Kyu, kyu, something's wrong! Stop it!
おらおらおら！なんか違う！なんか違う！
Take that! Something's different! Something's wrong!
ちょっと、時間もちょっと押してるからね
Hold on, we're running a bit short on time too
押してるんだ！
We're running short?!
綿飴、綿飴、ちょっと手引いて、前、前、前
Cotton candy, cotton candy, pull my hand, front, front, front
え、いいの？だって、おいしそうな匂いがするな
Huh, is that okay? Because it smells so delicious
なんか違う！おいしそうな匂いする！
Something's wrong! It smells so delicious!
あ、なんかいい！いいですね、どうです？
Ah, this is nice! It's nice, how is it?
スクショみんな撮れた？取れた？撮れた？プルプルプル！
Did everyone take a screenshot? Did you take it? Purupuru!
じゃあね、ちょっとごめんね、今日はね
Well, sorry everyone, today...
たくさんのゲストが来るから時間がね。あー、それはしょうがないですね。
Lots of guests are coming, so we don't have much time. Ah, well that can't be helped.
そう、ちょっと押しちゃったんだ。まあすぐ行きましょう、もう綿飴先輩！
Yeah, we ran a bit over. Well let's go right away, Cotton Candy-senpai!
ま、まだここにいる！え？あ、だめでしょう、それは。ここにいるんだもん！
W-wait, we're still here! Eh? Ah, you can't do that. We're right here!
帰りますよ！うちらだもん、だ。あ、いや。
We're going back! It's us, yeah. Ah, no.
もうこうなったらね、うちらで食べちゃいましょう。
Well since it's come to this, let's just eat it ourselves.
そっか。え？食べられたいってことだな？そうね。
I see. Huh? You want to be eaten? That's right.
いや、そういうことじゃねえよ！いい匂いするね君ね。
No, that's not what I mean! You smell nice.
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
Enjoy, the music keeps playing,
IT'S JOIN 届けたい 胸の鼓動
It's join, I want to reach your heartbeat.
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance(READY GO!)
Heart dances, raising the encore, Dance Dance Dance, Ready Go!
今ゴーイング ゴールインより 飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Now going, leaping past the goal-in, riding the sound, keeping on swimming.
ENJOY(ENJOY) IT'S JOIN(IT'S JOIN) 呼応する 心響き続ける
Enjoy, It's join, echoing, our hearts keep resonating.
のっけから的な言葉が出てきた ここは心躍る場所だから置いてかないよ 欲しいなら Get Up Stand Up
Words came out right from the start, this is a place where hearts dance, so we won't leave you behind, if you want it, Get Up Stand Up.
行くしかねえ つかねえ やっぱ気づいたんだ 100% 幸せの意思表示 鳴らせ CLAP CLAP 仲間同士 夜通し 詰め込んで
Gotta go, gotta grab it, I realized after all, 100% expression of happiness, ring out, clap clap, friends all night long, packing it in.
Have a dreamin' グリーディング
Have a dreamin' greeting,
この場の空気 中心 サークル 繋がり ブギア フリーキー きばらす
the atmosphere of this place, center circle, connecting boogie, freaky, pushing forward.
ここみんなと その価値あるから Swing swing sing a song
Here with everyone, because it has that value, Swing swing sing a song.
真面目 恥ずかしがりでもできる イマジネーション 望むところだ 茶の間どころか所構わず ボタンひとつで踊る心が
Imagination that even a serious, shy person can do, exactly what I hoped for, not just the living room, anywhere, with just a button, a heart that dances.
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
Enjoy, the music keeps playing,
IT'S JOIN 届けたい 胸の鼓動
It's join, I want to reach your heartbeat.
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance(READY GO!)
Heart dances, raising the encore, Dance Dance Dance, Ready Go!
今ゴーイング ゴールインより 飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Now going, leaping past the goal-in, riding the sound, keeping on swimming.
ENJOY(ENJOY) IT'S JOIN(IT'S JOIN) 呼応する 心響き続ける
Enjoy, It's join, echoing, our hearts keep resonating.
やっぱりな針や 俺は急いで歯を磨く 手間は取らせんさ みな あみだす つかかっても 心騒ぎ出す 時間 場所など限らず
As expected, hurry up, I'm in a hurry to brush my teeth, I won't waste your time, everyone, creating it, even if it gets tough, heart starts roaring, regardless of time or place,
グータラ てきぱき 日常 メリハリ 毎日 変わる音 フレッシュ デリバリー 揺らす body rock 増々 ベクター 向かう 矛先 は プラス へ その 長 と 短 そこ が どうか なる 所々
lazy or prompt, daily life, everyday sounds change, fresh delivery, shaking body rock, more and more vector, the destination points to plus, its long and short, wherever that may be.
ココロ ゴト 転がし あう だから 今日 は 今日 振り切る 昨日 心から 踊らす この 一時 一度
Rolling hearts together, so today we shake off yesterday, dancing from the bottom of our hearts this once-in-a-lifetime moment.
go ドア 開けたら フロア 浮き足立つ 抜け出す 揺れる core up and down
Go, when you open the door, the floor gets excited, slipping out, swaying core up and down.
こっち向き タント タップ let's dance come on 加速 構う もん か
Facing this way, tanto tap, let's dance, come on, acceleration, who cares?
もういいても たってもいらんない 心だけじゃ収んない 日々 day and night shake a body ぎこちないなら ないで可愛い 今日から 感じるままに
Even if I stay or go, I can't contain it with just my heart, days day and night shake a body, if it's awkward, that's cute too, feeling it as it is from today.
live life good to be alive
笑い 愛し合えりど 愛 ラビズム おとことことば 繋ぐこの場
Laughing, loving each other, love rhythm, connecting men and words in this place.
届いてるなら make some noise
If it's reaching you, make some noise!
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
Enjoy, the music keeps playing,
IT'S JOIN 届けたい 胸の鼓動
It's join, I want to reach your heartbeat.
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance(READY GO!)
Heart dances, raising the encore, Dance Dance Dance, Ready Go!
今ゴーイング ゴールインより 飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Now going, leaping past the goal-in, riding the sound, keeping on swimming.
ENJOY(ENJOY) IT'S JOIN(IT'S JOIN) 呼応する 心響き続ける
Enjoy, It's join, echoing, our hearts keep resonating.
グレートフル 描く スケール は でかく 楽しい もん だ エラク デラックス
Grateful, drawing a scale big, it's a fun thing, elite, deluxe.
狙う 暇 なんか 単純に 簡単 預け とけ アンド カウントダウン
No time to aim, simply easy, leave it and countdown.
3 2 1 なりふり 構わず 夢中 で 駆け抜けろ
3, 2, 1, running through passionately without caring about appearances.
息 まい て it's like this さらに 深い 感動 へ モーレツ oh yes
Catching my breath, it's like this, towards an even deeper emotion, furiously oh yes.
ココロオドル 今日 へ
Towards a heart-dancing today,
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
Enjoy, the music keeps playing,
IT'S JOIN 届けたい 胸の鼓動
It's join, I want to reach your heartbeat.
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance(READY GO!)
Heart dances, raising the encore, Dance Dance Dance, Ready Go!
今ゴーイング ゴールインより 飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Now going, leaping past the goal-in, riding the sound, keeping on swimming.
ENJOY(ENJOY) IT'S JOIN(IT'S JOIN) 呼応する 心響き続ける
Enjoy, It's join, echoing, our hearts keep resonating.
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
Enjoy, the music keeps playing,
IT'S JOIN 届けたい 胸の鼓動
It's join, I want to reach your heartbeat.
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance(READY GO!)
Heart dances, raising the encore, Dance Dance Dance, Ready Go!
今ゴーイング ゴールインより 飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Now going, leaping past the goal-in, riding the sound, keeping on swimming.
ENJOY(ENJOY) IT'S JOIN(IT'S JOIN) 呼応する 心響き続ける
Enjoy, It's join, echoing, our hearts keep resonating.
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance(READY GO!)
Heart dances, raising the encore, Dance Dance Dance, Ready Go!
今ゴーイング ゴールインより 飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
Now going, leaping past the goal-in, riding the sound, keeping on swimming.
ENJOY(ENJOY) IT'S JOIN(IT'S JOIN) 呼応する 心響き続ける
Enjoy, It's join, echoing, our hearts keep resonating.
ちょっとね、今日はみんなで水着を着たので、
Since we're all wearing swimsuits today,
ちょっとね、スクショタイムをしたいなと。
we wanted to have a screenshot time!
踊るわよ！
We're gonna dance!
踊る？踊る？
Dancing? Dancing?
夏っぽいポーズ。
A summery pose.
夏っぽいポーズ？
A summery pose?
え、夏？こういうの？
Um, summer? Like this?
ビーチバレーみたいな？そう。
Like beach volleyball? Yeah.
ビーチバレーみたいなね。
Like beach volleyball.
あ、撮れ！
Ah, take it!
撮れるもんなら撮ってみろ！
Take it if you can!
撮れた？
Did you get it?
撮れたかなあ。
I wonder if we got it.
無理か。
Impossible?
無理だろ、無理だな。
No way, definitely impossible.
大丈夫かな？
Will it be okay?
あと徐々に、3人でちょっと固まってなんか撮りたいな。
Also, gradually, the three of us should group up and take one.
撮りたい！
We want to take it!
おお？
Oh?
おお、かわいい！
Oh, cute!
じゃあね、せっかくね、ちょっと3人、我々しっぽがあるので、
Since the three of us all have tails,
あ、確かに！
Ah, true!
しっぽ！
Tails!
撮って撮って！
Take a picture!
あ、あ、
Ah, ah,
ちょっと次の現場があるんで。
We have our next gig coming up.
次の現場へ、やあやあやあやあ！
To the next site, ya ya ya ya!
先に行くぜ！やあやあ！
We're going ahead! Ya ya!
おめでとう、やあ！
Congrats, ya!
ありがとう、やあ！
Thanks, ya!
言の葉を紡いで 微笑んだうたたか
Weaving words together with a gentle smile,
まどろんだうたたか
dozing off in a dreamy haze,
旅人迷い込み 御伽の深い霧
a traveler strays into a deep fairytale fog.
差し伸べた手のひら そっと触れる予感
A premonition of gently touching an outstretched palm,
受け止めて零れた 光の一雫
catching a single falling drop of light.
面影移ろって 微笑んだ幻
Features shifting, a smiling phantom,
思いの当たる場所 まだ遥か遠くて
the place where my thoughts lead is still far away,
幾千幾万幾億の旋律となる
becoming thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of melodies.
求め探ししてさ迷って やがて歌われて
searching, wandering, until eventually turned into song,
いつか失い奪われて消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to be lost and fade away someday,
それは忘れられることなし物語
it is a story that will never be forgotten.
指先を絡めて 触れる誰かの夢
Entwining fingertips, touching someone's dream,
刻まれた思いの 木霊だけが響く
only the echo of inscribed thoughts resonates.
言の葉を紡いで 微笑んだうたたか
Weaving words together with a gentle smile,
旅人の名前を 御伽話と言う
calling the traveler's name a fairytale.
求め探ししてさ迷って やがて道となり
Searching, wandering, eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は行く
thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of heroes march on.
いつか失い奪われて消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to be lost and fade away someday,
それは忘れられることなしここに在る
the story is saved here without being forgotten.
指先をもからべて 触れる誰かの夢
Entwining fingertips, touching someone's dream,
刻まれた思いの こだまだけが響く
only the echo of inscribed thoughts resonates.
言の葉を紡いで まどろんだうたたか
Weaving words together in a dreamy haze,
旅人の名前を 御伽話と言う
calling the traveler's name a fairytale.
言の葉を紡いで 微笑んだうたたか
Weaving words together with a gentle smile,
旅人の名前を 御伽話と言う
calling the traveler's name a fairytale.
求め探ししてさ迷って やがて道となり
Searching, wandering, eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は行く
thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of heroes march on.
求め探ししてさ迷って やがて道となり
Searching, wandering, eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は行く
thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of heroes march on.
いつか失い奪われて消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to be lost and fade away someday,
それは忘れられることなしここに在る
the story is saved here without being forgotten.
求め探ししてさ迷って やがて道となり
Searching, wandering, eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は行く
thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of heroes march on.
いつか失い奪われて消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to be lost and fade away someday,
それは忘れられることなしここに在る
the story is saved here without being forgotten.
求め探ししてさ迷って やがて道となり
Searching, wandering, eventually becoming a path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は行く
thousands, tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of heroes march on.
今見上げてる 輝きたちは
These shimmering lights we gaze up at now
何年もの遥か 旅をしてきた
Have traveled from years, far away
暗闇を越え たどり着いたんだ
Crossing the darkness, they finally arrived
届けたいメッセージ 一つずつ握りしめて
Holding tight to each message we want to deliver
君と出会ったから 一つの光になる
Since I met you, it becomes a single light
あの星と星は 遠く離れて呼び合っていた
Those stars were calling out to each other from afar
それぞれの違った 色のままで 宇宙に大きな彩を描いて
Each in their own colors, painting a grand canvas across the universe
誰かの望んだ 未来が 繋がっていると信じたなら
If we believe that the futures someone wished for are connected
きっとその手が 放つ光
Surely, the light released from those hands
同じあなたの 見果てぬ夢を
Seeking out the same unseen dreams as you
幾千の中から 見つけられるよ
From thousands of possibilities, I can find them
諦めない勇気 その眩しさが
The dazzling courage of never giving up
ここにいるんだって 気付かせてくれたときに
Made me realize that I am right here
君のまなざしが まっすぐに見てるなら
If your gaze looks straight ahead
そう星と星のように 誰もが呼び合えるんだ
Just like stars, anyone can call out to each other
それぞれに希望の色を持って 明日という名の彩を描いて
Holding hopes of their own colors, painting tomorrow's dawn
自分の選んだ誓いと 誰かの望んだ未来が
With the oath you chose and someone's wished-for future
重なり合っていること 感じるのは
Feeling how they intertwine and overlap
きっとその手が 放つ光
Surely, the light released from those hands
その手が その手が たとえ 奇跡だけが
Even if miracles alone...
新しい聖座をつくって
Forge new constellations
物語をまた繋ぎでゆく
And weave the story together once more
そう星と星は 遠く離れて呼び合ってるんだ
Those stars were calling out to each other from afar
それぞれが違った 色のままで 宇宙に大きな彩を描いて
Each in their own colors, painting a grand canvas across the universe
誰かが望んだ 未来が 輝いていけるときと信じたから
Believing in the time when the future someone wished for can shine bright
きっと君なら 届くはるか遠くへ
Surely, if it's you, you'll reach far away
放つ光
The shining light
ボタンちゃん！
Botan-chan!
2周年！
2nd Anniversary!
おめでとうだよー！
Congratulations!
ありがとうだよー！
Thank you!
ラララ オン
La la la on...
おめでとうだよー！ / ありがとうだよー！
Congratulations! / Thank you!
花の色彩が変えられるほどの
As flowers change colors,
永い時間の密度に近くて
So close to the density of long time,
フレームは一瞬スローモーションで
The frame is a moment in slow motion,
一直線光裂くように
A straight line, like a light tearing through,
空気を揺らし鼓動を鳴らせ
Shaking the air, making the heartbeat ring,
静かな夜に今火をつけるの
I light a fire in the silent night now,
恋ともぜんぜん違うエモーション
An emotion completely different from love,
ホントにそれだけなの…
It's really just that...
火花のようにFLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
早い時間の中でちちはやぶる
In the midst of the fastest time,
FLASH光る
FLASH shines,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
舞い散る落ち葉が地に着くまでの
As dancing fallen leaves reach the ground,
刹那的な速度に近くて
So close to a momentary speed,
フレームは一瞬ハイスピードで
The frame is at high speed for a moment,
一直線光裂くように
A straight line, like a light tearing through,
空気を揺らし鼓動を鳴らせ
Shaking the air, making the heartbeat ring,
静かな夜に今火をつけるの
I light a fire in the silent night now,
恋ともぜんぜん違うエモーション 今夜は
An emotion completely different from love tonight...
火花のようにFLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
早い時間の中でちちはやぶる
In the midst of the fastest time,
FLASH光る
FLASH shines,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
かざした手を弓矢に変えて
Turn your hand into a bow and arrow,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
願う真空の間で届きそうだFLASH
I wish I could reach it in the vacuum, FLASH.
真っ逆さまガチに付くまでの
As it falls headlong until it hits,
切なすぎる程の速度に近くて
So close to a painfully intense speed,
フレームは一瞬ハイスピードで
The frame is at high speed for a moment,
一直線光裂くように
A straight line, like a light tearing through,
空気を揺らし鼓動を鳴らせ
Shaking the air, making the heartbeat ring,
静かな夜に今火をつけるの
I light a fire in the silent night now,
恋ともぜんぜん違うエモーション
An emotion completely different from love,
火花のようにFLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
今夜はこれからの
Tonight is from now on...
FLASH光る
FLASH shines,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
かざした手を弓矢に変えて
Turn your hand into a bow and arrow,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
願う真空の間で届きそうだFLASH
I wish I could reach it in the vacuum, FLASH.
火花のようにFLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
早い時間の中でちちはやぶる
In the midst of the fastest time,
FLASH光る
FLASH shines,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
かざした手を弓矢に変えて
Turn your hand into a bow and arrow,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
願う真空の間で届きそうだFLASH
I wish I could reach it in the vacuum, FLASH.
FLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
早い時間の中でちちはやぶる
In the midst of the fastest time,
ちはやぶる
Chihayaburu
火花のようにFLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
早い時間の中でちちはやぶる
In the midst of the fastest time,
FLASH光る
FLASH shines,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
かざした手を弓矢に変えて
Turn your hand into a bow and arrow,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
願う真空の間で届きそうだFLASH
I wish I could reach it in the vacuum, FLASH.
火花のようにFLASH光る
Shines like a spark, FLASH,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
鳴らし出した音も置き去りにして
Leaving behind the sound we started,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
早い時間の中でちちはやぶる
In the midst of the fastest time,
FLASH光る
FLASH shines,
最高のLightning Game
The best Lightning Game,
かざした手を弓矢に変えて
Turn your hand into a bow and arrow,
FLASH超える
Surpassing FLASH,
最高のLightning Speed
The best Lightning Speed,
願う真空の間で届きそうだFLASH
I wish I could reach it in the vacuum, FLASH.
FLASH
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
なんかね、ぺこら先輩のライブにも出たし、とわのライブにも出て
You know, I appeared in Pekora-senpai's live, and Towa's live too,
3回目よ。
so this is my third time.
え、なにご？
Huh, what number?
え、だから、7月5日、8月5日でペポと急におつまとびして、
Uh, so, July 5th and August 5th, Peko and I suddenly got together—
集まったね！
We did get together!
確かね。
That's right.
じゃ、次の記念日の人、はい。
Now, the person with the next anniversary, yes.
はーい！
Here!
とわ！1月3日！
Towa! January 3rd!
1月12…あ、1月だ！
January 12— Ah, January!
えーっと、9月なんだけ…
Um, September, but...
じゃ、9月は、どうかな？最終号できるかな？
Well, September, I wonder? Can we do a final issue?
確かに。
True.
じゃ、よいおって感じ？
Like, "Have a good year" vibe?
よいお年？
Have a good year?
え、もしかしてそれまで集まんないてこと？
Wait, does that mean we won't meet until then?
なんか最近ちょっとだって、ライブばっかぺこどくろす…
Lately, it's just been live after live...
ライブしか集まらん！
We only get together for lives!
ペポっとライブでしか集まらない説
The theory that we only gather for lives!
えー、でもまあ、あの、じゃあ来年もよいお年をということで、はい。
Um, but well, then have a good year for next year too, yes.
よいお年を！早い早い！
Have a good year! Way too early!
本当に来るの？
Are you really coming?
うん。
Yeah.
帰るか。
Time to go home.
帰ろう。早い早い。
Let's go home. Way too early.
たらりよ、たらりよ…
Tarariyo, tarariyo...
unlasting 作詞:LiSA 作曲:草野華余子
unlasting / Lyrics: LiSA / Music: Kayoko Kusano
一人きりでも平気とこぼれ落ちた強がり
An empty assurance escapes my lips, pretending I'll be fine by myself.
二人の眩しすぎた日がこんなに悲しい
Those days when the two of us shone too bright now bring me so much sorrow.
一人で生きられるなら誰かを愛したりしないから
If I was capable of living life all alone, I never would have loved in the first place.
あなたの香り あなたの話し方
Your scent, the way you speak—
今も身体中に“愛のカケラ”が残ってるよ
"Fragments of love" still remain all over my body.
私の願い 私の願いはただ…
My wish, my only wish is...
どうか貴方もどこかで泣いていますように
That you, wherever you are, are crying too.
いつも新しい一歩は重くて寂しい
The first step of something new is always heavy and lonely.
もし生まれ変わってももう一度あなたに出逢いたい
Even if I were born again, I'd want to meet you once more.
真夏の日差しの真冬の白い雪
Midsummer sunlight and midwinter white snow—
巡る季節中に“愛のカケラ”が舞い落ちて
"Fragments of love" flutter down through the turning seasons.
幸せなのにどこかで寂しいのは
The reason why I'm happy yet feel so lonely somewhere inside
貴方よりも大きな私の愛のせい
is because my love for you is greater than yours.
鍵はあなたが持ったまま
You still hold the key.
一人きりでも
Even if I am on my own,
平気とこぼれ落ちた強がり
the pretense of strength just spills right out.
二人の眩しすぎた日が こんなに悲しい
To think the days we shone together could be so sad...
一人で生きられるなら
If I could live alone,
誰かを愛したりしないから
I wouldn't have to love anyone else.
あなたの香り あなたの話し方
Your scent and the way you talk—
今も身体中に“愛のカケラ”が残ってるよ
even now, fragments of love remain inside me.
私の願い 私の願いはただ…
My only wish, my only wish is simply...
どうか あなたが幸せでありますように
that somewhere, you are crying, too, and are happy.
いつも新しい一歩は 重くて寂しい
Every new step I take is so heavy and lonely.
もし生まれ変わっても もう一度あなたに出会いたい
If I were reborn, I'd want to meet you once again.
真夏の日差し 真冬の白い雪
Midsummer sunshine, midwinter white snow.
巡る季節の中に…
In the turning seasons...
空飛ぶ羽根と引き換えに 繋ぎ合う手を選んだ僕ら
We chose hands to hold instead of wings to fly through the sky.
それでも空に魅せられて 夢を重ねるのは罪か
Even so, fascinated by the sky, is dreaming a sin?
夏は秋の背中を見て その顔を思い浮かべる
Summer watches autumn's back, picturing its face.
憧れなのか 恋なのか 叶わぬと知りながら
Is it longing? Is it love? Knowing it won't come true.
重力が眠りにつく 1000年に一度の今日
On this millennium-once-in-a-lifetime day when gravity falls asleep,
太陽の死角に立ち 僕らこの星を出よう
let's stand in the sun's blind spot and leave this star.
彼が目を覚ました時 連れ戻せない場所へ
To a place we can't return once he wakes his eyes.
「せーの」で大地を蹴って ここではない星へ行こう
On three, let's kick the earth and go to another star!
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a little more beyond fate.
もう少しで文明の向こう
Just a little more beyond civilization.
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a little more beyond fate.
もう少しで…
Just a little more...
夢に僕らで帆を張って 来るべき日のために夜を越え
We'll hoist our sails with dreams, crossing the night for the days to come.
いざ期待だけ満タンで あとはどうにかなるさと肩を組んだ
Full of expectations, arms linked, whatever happens will happen.
怖くないわけない でも 止まらない
It's not that we aren't scared, but we won't stop.
ピンチの先回りしたって 僕らしようがないから
Even if trouble looms ahead, we have no other choice.
僕らの恋が言う 声が言う
Our love speaks, our voice speaks:
「行け」と言う
"Go," it says.
夏は秋の背中を見て その顔を思い浮かべる
Summer looks at autumn's back, picturing its face.
憧れなのか 恋なのか 叶わぬと知りながら
Is it longing? Is it love? Knowing it won't come true.
重力が眠りにつく 1000年に一度の今日
On this millennium-once-in-a-lifetime day when gravity falls asleep,
太陽の死角に立ち 僕らこの星を出よう
let's stand in the sun's blind spot and leave this star.
彼が目を覚ました時 連れ戻せない場所へ
To a place we can't return once he wakes his eyes.
「せーの」で大地を蹴って ここではない星へ行こう
On three, let's kick the earth and go to another star!
行こう 行こう 行こう
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
夏風に焦る心が
Let's match our hearts to the summer wind,
夏をさらに遠く送るよ
sending summer even further ahead.
目まぐるしい景色の中
In the dizzying scenery,
君だけ止まって見えた
Only you seemed to be standing still.
君と出会ったあの日から
Ever since the day I met you,
パタリと夜、夢は止んだよ
suddenly my night dreams stopped.
土の中で待ちこがれた
Waiting and yearning within the soil,
叶えるその時は今だ
the time to fulfill it is now.
重力が眠りにつく 1000年に一度の今日日
On this once-in-a-millennium day when gravity falls asleep,
花火の音に乗せ 僕らこの星を出よう
riding on the sound of fireworks, let's leave this star.
彼が目を覚ました時 連れ戻せない場所へ
To a place he can't bring us back from when he opens his eyes,
「せーの」で大地を蹴っ飛ばして ここではない星へ
on three, let's kick off the earth and head for a different star!
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a little bit farther beyond destiny,
もう少しで文明の向こう
just a little bit farther beyond civilization.
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a little bit farther beyond destiny,
もう少しで
just a little bit farther...
夢に僕らで帆を張って
We'll spread these sails together, filled with our dreams,
来るべき日のために夜を越え
and cross the night to reach the day that must come.
いざ期待だけ満タンで あとはどうなる事さと肩を組んだ
Our hopes alone are full to the brim, arms locked, ready for whatever comes.
恐くないわけない でも止まない
It's not that we aren't scared, but we won't stop.
夢に僕らで帆を張って
We'll spread these sails together, filled with our dreams,
来るべき日のために夜を越え いざ行きたいだけ満タンで
and cross the night to reach the day, our eagerness filled to the brim.
あとはどうにかなるさと肩を組んだ 怖くない
Arms locked, knowing we'll get through it somehow, it's not that we're scared—
わけないでしょ とまんない
of course we are, but we won't stop!
ピーチの先回り 従ってた
Running ahead of the pitch, we followed along;
僕らじゃしょうがない 僕らの
there's nothing we can do, it's our—
声が言う 声が言う
voice that speaks, our voice speaks:
行けと言う
"Go!" it says.
もう少しで文明の向こう
Just a little bit farther beyond civilization...
イエー！どれだけいいえいうねんま？
Yay! How many "Ie" did we say?!
ということで、僕たちでグランドエスケープをお届けさせていただきました！
And with that, we delivered "Grand Escape" for you all!
さっきまでやれもなかったのに、もうこんなになってる。
Up until a minute ago we couldn't do this, and now we're like this.
え、ていうことでね、え、活動記念も... 2年経ちまして、2周年...
And so, um, our activity anniversary... 2 years have passed, 2nd anniversary...
いやもう本当早いんだけど、ま、ね、今後も動きでね、色々わちゃわちゃやっていけたら
It really is fast, but we hope to keep moving and having fun together like this in the future too.
嬉しいなと。いつも通りね！
We'd be so happy. As always!
じゃあね、じゃあ、次の3年目も動きで歌いたいから、ちょっと来てくれよな！
Well then, for our 3rd year too we want to sing actively, so please come along!
えい！いいぞー！え、じゃあ、またシャボンドショーで会おう。
Yeah! Great! Well then, let's meet again at Shabond-show.
お、宝箱見つけていくか。なん... ビブルカードをね。
Oh, shall we go find treasure chests? We got Vivre Cards...
十国！
Jukoku!
さてさて、配信の途中ですが、重大な告知が2つあります！
Now then, in the middle of the stream, we have two major announcements!
まず1つ目は、こちら！獅白ぼたん2周年記念グッズ発売です！イエーイ！
First is this! Shishiro Botan's 2nd Anniversary merchandise is now on sale! Yay!
じゃあね、ちょっと簡単にですけど、1つずつ紹介していきます。
Now, I'll briefly introduce them one by one.
まず1つ目は、こちら！え、バスタオルです！
First is this! Um, a bath towel!
東西先生のかっこいいデザインが光るバスタオル、こちらね、もう拭いてよし、飾ってよし。
A bath towel featuring a cool design by Tonzai-sensei. This is great for drying off or displaying!
もうバスタオルだから、なんだろう、汚れたら洗えるし、あとまデザインもかっこいいから、
Since it's a bath towel, you can wash it if it gets dirty, and the design is cool,
なんかね、体ふくだけじゃなくてさ、お部屋に飾るとかさ、ノリにしするとかさ、
so instead of just drying your body, you can decorate your room with it, use it as a tapestry,
なんか、布団に引いてみるとかさ、
or even put it on your futon!
色々な活用方法があると思うので、ぜひよかったら愛用してください。
There are so many ways to use it, so please use and cherish it!
これね、かっこいいよね。で、続いてはステッカーです！
This is really cool, right? Next is the sticker!
こちらもね、えっとサイズが297×大体200mm。
This also has a size of around 297 x 200 mm.
できました。こちらは1つ購入すると、ランダムで1種類お届けする形となります。
Got it! If you purchase one, you'll receive one at random.
キーホルダーの種類ですが、工事看板SSRB、ショッピングカートSSRB、
As for the keychains, we have a construction sign SSRB, a shopping cart SSRB,
ししろん に無理やりロボットとかされたSSRB、どういう状況だて感じなんですけど、
and an SSRB forcibly turned into a robot—what kind of situation is this?
そして、いえけいSSRBの4種類となっておりますので、ぜひこちらねコンプリートしてくれたら嬉しいなと思っております。
and four types of Iekei SSRB! So I'd be really happy
もうこれは複数買い推奨です。自分できっちゃいますけど。
if you could complete the set. I recommend buying multiple!
で、最後はこちらSSRBソックス！シンプルで使いやすいデザインの靴下となっております。
And lastly, we have these SSRB socks! Simple and easy-to-use design socks.
ワンポイントでねSSRBの刺繍とSSRBの書き下ろしロゴがついてます。このふにゃっとしたね可愛いロゴが
They feature a cute embroidered SSRB and SSRB's drawn logo as a nice accent.
あるので、ねこれ履いて、まあ仕事だったり学校だったり遊びだったり色んな場所にねSSRBを連れて行ってくれると嬉しいです。
I hope you'll take SSRB with you to work, school, or wherever you go!
そして今回周年記念グッズのフルセットを購入していただいた方には、おっと？
And for those who purchase the full set, an autographed postcard bonus is included!
なんとなんと！新曲が出まーす！ここで発表です！
And now... a new song is coming out! Announcing it right here!
ということで、曲名はですね、iii love you！ いい曲だと思うんだよな、私は。
So, the title of the song is "III Love You"! I think it's a great song.
こちら8月14日の24時、まあつまりね、今日の0時ですね、各種音楽配信サイトで聞けるようになります。
It will be available on various music streaming sites starting today at midnight.
このさっき言ったね曲名iii love youのねタイトルをちょっと口ずさみたくなるような歌かもと個人的には思ってるんですが、どうでしょうかね？
I personally hope it's the kind of song whose title you'll want to hum along to.
ちょっとその辺はね聞いてみてください。でね良かったらぜひTwitterで感想を聞かせてもらえると嬉しいです。
Be sure to give it a listen, and I'd love to hear your thoughts on Twitter!
以上重大告知2つでした！ありがとうございました！
That's all for the two major announcements! Thank you!
ということで、オリジナル曲に、グッズに、いっぱい出るんで皆さんよかったらぜひグッズは買って下さいオリジナル曲は聞いてください。よろしくお願いします！
Original songs and merchandise are coming out, so please check them out and listen!
えーいよいよね次の曲が最後となりますので、いっぱい練習してきたのでいっぱい見て聞いてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
This will be the final song, and I've practiced a lot for it, so I hope you enjoy it!
よし！いくぞ！最後の曲だ！
Alright, let's go! The final song!
stop motion stop emotion
oh ! please kill me
Oh! Please kill me
新しい私で まだ泣けない 終わりに出来ないわ
As a new me, I still can't cry, I can't end it here.
こんなに愛してるのに
Even though I love you this much,
悲しい程聞こえる素直な声
I hear my honest voice so painfully clearly.
見慣れた人ごみの街に 無口な男のさようならだから
In the familiar crowded streets, it's a silent man's goodbye.
どこか彼女を感じたの 理由を言わない優しさが今
I somehow sensed another woman. Your unspoken kindness right now
息が止まる程痛い せめてもう一度
Hurts so much it takes my breath away. At least once more—
here is last my wish , this moment yeah , yeah , yeah , yeah
Here is my last wish, this moment, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
stop motion stop emotion
oh ! please kill me
Oh! Please kill me
新しい私で未来を夢見たい
I want to dream of the future as a new me.
膝をかかえて待ち疲れた夜明け
Holding my knees, waiting tirelessly for dawn,
あなたのdoorに頬寄せて
I pressed my cheek against your door
微笑んで手を振ったらきっと 思い出に変えられるはず
And smiled as I waved goodbye—surely we could have turned it into a memory.
わかっていても愛しさの鼓動 私にも止められないから
Even knowing that, the heartbeat of love can't be stopped by me either.
もう一度
Once more—
here is last my wish , this moment yeah , yeah , yeah , yeah
Here is my last wish, this moment, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
stop motion stop emotion
ah 殺してほしい
Ah, I want you to kill me.
oh ! please kill me
Oh! Please kill me
狂おしく強く溶け合ったままで
Remaining madly and strongly melted together,
stop motion stop emotion
どんな悲しみも乗り越えてゆけるのに
No matter how deep the sadness is, I can overcome it...
乗り越えてゆけるのに
I'll keep going through it all.
抱えている願いの重さに
Carrying the heavy burden of my wishes,
追い付けない もどかしさが胸を潰す
this frustration crushes my heart.
痛いくらい あなたへの想い膨らんでく
My feelings for you grow so painful.
叶えるのなら
If my wish could come true,
もう一度 抱き締め付けて
please hold me tight just once more.
あなたが触れた温もりが離れないから
The warmth of your touch never leaves me.
I just pray that "stop my lies."
涙の答えは
Seeking an answer to my tears,
明日を占う 闇に問いかけてみる
I question the darkness that clouds tomorrow.
苦しいくらい 真直ぐな想い
With feelings so pure and painful,
伝えられるような 強い勇気が欲しい…
I wish I had the courage to tell you.
I just pray that "stop my cry."
涙の粒には
In every single teardrop,
あなたへと向かう想いが揺らめいている
my feelings waver toward you.
許されるなら見つめ続けたい
If you'll allow me, I want to keep watching you
いつかこの胸が壊れてしまう日まで
until the day this heart shatters completely.
涙の跡には
In the traces of my tears,
消せない想いが 乾いた光放つ
an unfading memory shines like dry light.
あなたの側で 生きてゆけるなら
If I can live by your side,
どんな悲しみも 乗り越えてゆけるのに
no matter how deep the sadness is,
いつかこの胸が壊れてしまう日まで
Until the day this heart shatters.
3年目も一緒に楽しもうね！
Let's enjoy our 3rd year together too!